<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DS Squad Project Wiki</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DS Squad Project Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Git and our GitHub repositories</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-21-getting-started-with-git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-21-getting-started-with-git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Download Git and create a GitHub account  Download Git Create a GitHub account  Data Science Squad GitHub Organization The Data Science Squad Organization is a centralized collection of official repositories for our project. The Organization contains separate repositories for each project deliverable to promote organization and minimize interference between team members. All team members should accept their invitations to join the Organization. Though team members will work with their primary repositories most often, all team members will have the opportunity to contribute to other repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Branching</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-feature-branching-git-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-feature-branching-git-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Feature branching describes the process of creating Git branches for adding new features to the codebase without disturbing the main or develop branches within a remote repository. For example, website developers may create a feature branch called home-page specifically for building the home page of the website. Once completed, this feature branch can be merged into the production codebase through a formal review process.
Protecting the main and develop branches The main and develop branches represent our production (main) and development (develop) codebases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pull Requests</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-pull-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-pull-requests/</guid>
      <description>A Pull Request (PR) is a way to merge code from one branch into another through a formal review process. For example, if you develop code in a feature branch that needs to be merged into the develop branch, you will need to submit a PR and the repo administrator will either accept or reject the merge. This is the approach we will take to ensure the protected branches (main and develop) are maintained at a high standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack workspace and Trello board</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-slack-workspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-slack-workspace/</guid>
      <description>Our DS Squad Slack workspace is our primary communication platform. Use our Slack workspace to send messages to the group, @mention team members, send direct messages, and share files.
Trello is our Kanban-style tool for organizing and displaying the tasks we are working on, tasks that need to get done, and which team members are working on them. Use our Trello Task Tracker Board to help the team stay informed and monitor our progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production automation pipeline (in progress)</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-03-03-production-automation-pipeline-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-03-03-production-automation-pipeline-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>This document serves as a guide for all team members as we start to build out production assets and the production automation pipeline.
This is the current vision for the production automation pipeline:
![](images/Production pipeline.png)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging ML metrics in Neptune</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-27-logging-ml-metrics-in-neptune/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-27-logging-ml-metrics-in-neptune/</guid>
      <description>neptune.ai is a service for logging and tracking machine learning model metrics and performance. Neptune can be used during development to track experiments and compare models, and it can be used in production to monitor model performance with each new training run.
The following code snippets demonstrates the basic usage of neptune.ai.
Prerequisites Set the following environment variables to set a connection to our project workspace in Neptune. Contact Danny to obtain an API token.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productionizing the ML model</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-27-productionalizing-the-ml-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-27-productionalizing-the-ml-model/</guid>
      <description>The Machine Learning Engineers should use this document as a guide for converting your model into a production asset and automating it. Note that this process can be started whenever a prototype model is ready, even if you intend to improve upon the model.
The model should be on a daily release cycle, meaning each day the forecast model will be automatically re-run using new data (i.e. new crime incidents). This is made possible through the use of GitHub Actions, which is a feature within GitHub that triggers code to run in response to some &amp;ldquo;event&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating workflows with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-23-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-23-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Actions will make it easy to automate and orchestrate various workflows that drive our software. For our purposes, we will use GitHub Actions to trigger our production code to run in response to some automated event.
Examples:
  Every day, new crime incidents from the source API will be gathered and inserted into the database. This will trigger a &amp;ldquo;git push&amp;rdquo; event to the dssquad-ml repository.
  When the dssquad-ml repo receives the push event, GitHub Actions will automatically run a workflow to retrain the model, inserts new forecasts into the database, and logs accuracy metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure database connections and database queries using Python</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-secure-database-connections-using-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-secure-database-connections-using-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>Use the following code snippets to connect to our MySQL database in Python and submit database queries. Note that your credentials will need to be stored as environment variables to prevent sensitive information from being showin in plain text in the codebase.
To set environment variables in Python, use os.environ[&amp;quot;CASKEY5_USERNAME&amp;quot;] = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&amp;quot;. Note that this will save the environment variable for the current session only. If you begin a new Python session, the environment variables must be saved again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The who, what, why, and how of this project</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-24-the-who-what-why-and-how-of-this-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-24-the-who-what-why-and-how-of-this-project/</guid>
      <description>Who we are The Data Science Squad is a diverse, global team of data and analytics professionals who organized for the experience of developing a production-grade software product powered by machine learning.
The Team:
Nisrine Hammout - Machine Learning Engineer
Gayatri Dobhal - Machine Learning Engineer
Eric Caskey - Data Engineer
Melvin Sebastian - Data Engineer
Cassin Thangam Edwin - Data Visualization Engineer/Front-end Developer
Abdul-Mateen Qamardeen - Website Developer and QA Analyst</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
