<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on DS Squad Project Wiki</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on DS Squad Project Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Git and our GitHub repositories</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-21-getting-started-with-git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-21-getting-started-with-git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Download Git and create a GitHub account  Download Git Create a GitHub account  Data Science Squad GitHub Organization The Data Science Squad Organization is a centralized collection of official repositories for our project. The Organization contains separate repositories for each project deliverable to promote organization and minimize interference between team members. All team members should accept their invitations to join the Organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature branching Git workflow</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-feature-branching-git-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-feature-branching-git-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Feature branching describes the process of creating Git branches dedicated to specific project features without disturbing the main or develop branches within a repo. For example, website developers may create a feature branch called home-page for building the home page of the website. Once a Pull Request and code review have been completed, the feature branch is merged into the production codebase.
The main and develop branches in each repository should always be &amp;ldquo;deployable&amp;rdquo;, meaning these branches should only contain working code for either production (main) or dev/testing (develop).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pull Requests in GitHub to merge features into dev and prod codebases</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-pull-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-pull-requests/</guid>
      <description>A Pull Request (PR) is a way to merge code from one branch into another through a formal review process. For example, if you develop code in a feature branch that needs to be merged into the develop branch, you will need to submit a PR and the repo administrator will either accept or reject the merge. This is the approach we will take to ensure the protected branches (main and develop) are maintained at a high standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack workspace and Trello board</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-slack-workspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-slack-workspace/</guid>
      <description>Our DS Squad Slack workspace is our primary communication platform. Use our Slack workspace to send messages to the group, @mention team members, send direct messages, and share files.
Trello is our Kanban-style tool for organizing and displaying the tasks we are working on, tasks that need to get done, and which team members are working on them. Use our Trello Task Tracker Board to help the team stay informed and monitor our progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure database connections</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-02-20-secure-database-connections-using-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-02-20-secure-database-connections-using-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>For security reasons, use environment variables to store sensitive information and prevent it from being exposed in the codebase. This is recommended for local development and is required practice for pushing code to GitHub.
Python Set environment variables based on this example: os.environ[&amp;quot;CASKEY5_USERNAME&amp;quot;] = &amp;quot;my_database_username&amp;quot;
import osimport mysql.connectordb_uid = os.getenv(&#39;CASKEY5_USERNAME&#39;)db_pwd = os.getenv(&#39;CASKEY5_PASSWORD&#39;)db_host = os.getenv(&#39;CASKEY5_HOST&#39;)cnx = mysql.connector.connect(user=db_uid, password=db_pwd, host=db_host, database=&#39;caskey5_buffaloCrime&#39;)cnx.close()R  Set environment variables using Sys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
